本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多字幕下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
圣  城  风  云
『第一季  第九集』
翻译  Jasmine雪
翻译  LyraL
翻译  ala365
翻译  苏小黛
时间轴  veryink
后期  渔夫
特效  WiLL
总监制  苏小黛
早安
Good morning.
我疯了吗
Have I gone mad?
我肯定是疯了
不可能啊
It can't be there.
你是谁
What are you?
我就是你
I'm you.
你不可能是我
You can't be me.
你怎么可能是我
我是你的灵魂
I'm your soul.
你那肮脏不堪  满目疮痍的灵魂
Your dirty, damaged soul.
你知道你自己是什么货色
You know what you are.
知道你自己都干过什么
What you've done.
不  不
No. No!
好小子  我们会把你
Good lad! We'll
培养成卡米洛特的一名战士
make a Camelot warrior of you yet.
去取回来
Go fetch it.
-早安  -你好  阿尔比恩
- Morning. - Hello, Albion.
-真是个好小子  -是啊
- Good lad. - Aye.
早安
Good morning.
来拿啊
Come on.
来啊
Here you go.
快来啊
Come on.
放客气点
A bit more courtsey!
伙计  这里是巴尔东  从这里开始
eh, lads? This is Bardon Pass. From here on,
你们都在亚瑟王的庇护之下
you're under King Arthur's protection.
你们可以安置马匹  喝点水
You can rest your horses, get water--
这关口现在关闭了
This pass is closed.
-让他去  -父亲
- Let him go. - Father!
父亲  父亲
Father! Father!
你觉得练习这么一会儿就够了吗
You think that's enough time on target practice?
大门那里  守卫  都被杀害了
At the gate, the guards, they've been killed!
-准备好  -有十名突袭者
- Ready yourselves! - Ten attackers.
阿尔比恩  去后面的马厩找匹马
Albion, take the horse in the back barn.
你知道该怎么做的  快去
You know what to do. Move fast.
-是  父亲  -上帝与你同在
- Yes, Father. - God go with you.
威廉  威廉  过来
Willem! Willem, over here!
要派个人拦住他吗
Shall I send a man to dispatch him?
不用  让所有人就位
No. Get everyone in position.
那男孩做的正是我们想要的
That boy's doing exactly what they want.
好了  伙计们  跟上
All right, boys, follow us!
现在  华莱士  我们来看看
Now, Wallace, let's see
你都给我招募了些什么人吧
what type of men you've recruited for me.
我没疯  我没疯  我没疯
I'm not mad. I'm not mad. I'm not mad.
我没疯  我没疯
I'm not mad. I'm not mad.
我没疯  求你了  上帝  求你了
I'm not mad. Please, God. Please, God.
我没疯  我没疯
I'm not mad. I'm not mad.
-你去哪里了  -啊
- Where have you been? - Ah!
-梅林  -你怎么了
- Merlin! - What's happened to you?
你  你  你怎么在这儿
Wh-wh-what are you doing in here?
你的脸怎么了
What happened to your face?
我看到了我自己
I saw myself.
我直勾勾的盯着我自己
I was staring right back at me.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
伊格兰  伊格兰
Igraine. Igraine.
你去哪里了
Where have you been?
彭德拉根堡  那修女  她把我锁在
Castle Pendragon. The nun, she, she locked me up
一个房间里  把我囚禁在那里
in a room, and... held me prisoner, and...
-没人来救我  -嘘嘘
- No one came! - Shhhh.
伊格兰  伊格兰
Igraine. Igraine.
昨晚你在这里
You were here last night.
我们在一起
We were together.
不
No...
不  不  我杀了守卫
No. No, I killed a guard.
我偷了匹马逃回来  但却发现
I stole a horse, and then when I came back,
我正站在大厅里...
I was standing in the Great Hall, and...
-我知道自己做过什么  -不  不
- and I knew what I'd done. - No, no. No...
我早该看出来的
I should have seen.
我早该知道的
I should have known.
你和我  我
You and... me? I...
-我以为是这样  -可我
- So I thought. - But I...
我不记得了
I don't remember.
我不  梅林  我是不是疯了
I don't... Merlin, have I lost my mind?
没有  你没疯
No, you're not losing your mind.
-梅林  我  -是摩根在搞鬼
- Merlin, I... - It's Morgan!
这就是她囚禁你的原因
That's why she held you captive.
她来过这里
She's been here...
变成了你的模样  伊格兰
...wearing your face. Igraine,
我知道你受了很多苦
I know you've been through hell,
但我们得弄清  她在这里还做了什么
but we have to find out what else she did while she was here.
开门  是摩根
Open up! It's Morgan!
伊格兰逃跑了  她杀了守卫
Igraine escaped. She killed a guard.
我们说话这会她该在回卡米洛特的路上了
She'll be on her way back to Camelot as we speak.
我知道  我看到她了
I know; I saw her.
她看到你了吗
Did she see you?
她只看到了她自己
She only saw herself.
可怜的女人
Poor woman.
所有人都会以为她疯了
Everybody will think she's gone completely mad.
懦弱的人就是容易发疯
Well, madness so often afflicts the weak-minded.
怎么了
What's wrong?
你和国王之间发生过什么吗
Did something happen between you and the king?
别傻了
Oh, don't be ridiculous.
那就发誓
Then swear.
以上帝之名起誓  什么都没发生过
Swear on the holy word of God that nothing happened.
当然什么都没发生过
Of course nothing happened.
那就起誓
Then swear.
好
Fine.
我发誓
I swear...
发誓
...that...
我从未
...I never...
什么都没
...that nothing...
那没什么  什么都没发生过
It wasn't anything. There was nothing.
什么没什么
What was nothing?
告诉我
Tell me.
桂妮维尔  告诉我
Guinevere, tell me.
是在我们结婚之前
It was before we were married.
就那一次
It was only once.
我从来都不希望你知道这事
I never wanted you to know.
上帝  求你不要用那种眼神看我
Oh, God, please don't look at me like that.
-我受不了  -别
- I can't bare it!  - No.
什么时候
When?
在我成为你妻子之前
Before I was your wife.
可现在我们结婚了  我对你忠贞不二
But now we're married, and, and I'm loyal to you.
如果你对我还有感情  就跟我说实话
If you have any feelings for me, tell me when.
我们婚礼那天
On our wedding day.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我做了件很糟的事  但我仍是你妻子
I did a terrible thing, but I'm still your wife.
你不是我妻子
You're not my wife;
你是国王的情妇
you're the king's whore.
你还手啊
Hit me back!
还手啊
-让开  梅林  -里昂提斯
- Out of my way, Merlin. - Leontes...
-怎么回事  -是我和国王之间的恩怨
- What's happened? - My business is with the king.
国王的事就是我的事  过来和我说说
The king's business is mine also. Come here. Tell me.
伊格兰夫人  告诉了我实情
The Lady Igraine, she told me the truth.
什么
What?
亚瑟占有了我妻子
Arthur took my wife.
他和我妻子上床了
He had... my wife.
不可能
No.
难以置信
I can't believe this.
-她向我坦白了  -嘘
- She confessed to me!! - Shh!
国王必须回应他的所作所为
The king has to answer for what he's done.
如果确有其事
If this is true,
那亚瑟的所作所为无可饶恕
what Arthur has done is unforgivable.
可你想怎样呢  你要揍他吗
But what are you going to do? You're going to beat him?
割断他的喉咙吗
Slit his throat?
里昂提斯
Leontes,
你能咽下这口气的
you can bear this cross.
-我知道你可以  -我为何要忍气吞声
- I know you can. - Why should I?
回到桂妮维尔身边  让她自己赎罪吧
Go back to Guinevere. Let her absolve herself.
国王那边我来处理
I'll deal with the king.
你的事进行的怎样
What of your undertaking?
-成功了  -你确定吗
- It worked. - Are you sure?
卡米洛特已经受感染
Camelot is diseased.
我们就等着它病入膏肓吧
We will watch the plague spread.
巴尔东关口的行动已经开始
And the work at Bardon Pass has begun.
-其他的袭击也得跟上  -已经就位
- Other strikes must follow. - It is in motion.
他们已经到了
The men are here.
摩根小姐迫不及待的想与你们会面
My Lady Morgan is most anxious to see you.
我们也一样
So are we to see her.
亚瑟王未曾为我做什么 是您为我提供了
King Arthur's done nothing for me. It's you I owe right now
果腹的食物和居住的房屋  我亏欠您很多
for the food in my belly, and the roof over my head.
我请求您帮我收回我们领地的掌控权
I'm asking you to help me to claim back our land.
你要袭击卡米洛特吗
You want to make a strike on Camelot?
那可是叛国罪
That will be treason.
我们只寻求真理
We seek only to illuminate the truth.
亚瑟保护其子民的许诺是个谎言
Arthur's pledge of protection to his people is a lie.
如今西边边境的巴尔东正受到袭击
Even now his western border at Bardon Pass is under attack.
如果彭德拉根堡的北边  南边  东边
Should there be similar attacks on Pendragon outposts,
也受到相同的袭击
in the north, south, and east,
人们就会发现他们的防御是如此不堪一击
people would understand how fragile their security really is.
有钱领的话  我会清除一切障碍
I will take anything down, so long as there's payment.
重赏之下必有勇夫
Anyone can buy a man and his sword.
如果进行的顺利  皇土之内
If this is done well, the only safe place
将只有在我的羽翼下才是安全的
in the kingdom will be under my protection.
王位自然会落入我手中  而到那时
The crown will fall to me, and when it does,
我将会需要护卫和一位将军
I will need champions and a marshal...
那些投靠我的人
men whose investment to my rule
将得到比金钱更好回报
is greater than the gold in their purses.
那些起誓效忠我的人
Men who have pledged themselves to me,
将心  身
mind, body,
和魂都交予我的人
and soul.
我向你起誓
You have my pledge.
怎么了
What's the matter?
里昂提斯知道了  我们婚礼那天的事
Leontes knows. About us, about the wedding day.
他什么都知道了
He knows everything!
什么意思  他怎么知道的
What do you mean? How does he know?
-我告诉他了  -什么
- I told him. - What?!
他好像已经知道了似的
It's like he already knew!
你说什么了吗
Did you say something?
我从没对任何人说起
I never said anything to anyone!
那他是怎么知道的
Then how did he already know?
他在哪
Where is he?
-你只会越描越黑  -我得试着
- You'll only make it worse. - I have to try
跟他解释
and explain to him.
你能说什么啊
What could you possibly say?
说不是你的错  我强迫你的
That it wasn't your doing; I pressured you.
可那不是真的
That's not true.
我不能回避他
I can't avoid him.
他是我的朋友  我的护卫
He's my friend, my champion.
我们当初为何要那么做啊
Why did we ever do it?
里昂提斯是个好人
Leontes is a good man.
不会有事的
It'll be all right.
会的
It won't.
-她在干嘛  -在练习
- What's she doing? - She's practicing.
练习什么
Practicing what?
-自控能力  -这能有什么用
- Self control. - How will that help us?
我们绑架了国王的母亲
We kidnapped the king's mother.
你的惶恐对摩根毫无帮助
Your fear is useless to Morgan.
要么相信她  要么就走人
Giver her your faith or nothing at all.
但总会有报应的
But surely there will be retribution.
会的  所以我们要团结一致
There will be, and we must stand firm.
国王的母亲已经疯了
The king's mother has gone mad.
梅林孤掌难鸣了
Merlin is acting alone.
懂吗
Understand?
你见到国王的话  让他来找我
You see the king, you tell him to come and find me.
找到我前  不要让别人跟他说话
No one is to speak to him before I do.
-懂吗  -是
- Understand? - Right.
我知道他们彼此喜欢
I knew that they had eyes for each other,
但我不知道都到了这种程度
but I had no idea it had got to this.
可摩根却发现了
But Morgan did.
我需要你帮我摆平此事
I need your help to put this right.
这里的人仰仗你  向你吐露心声
People here rely on you, confide in you.
他们把你视作指引
They look to you as their guide.
那我该怎么做
Well, what can I do?
其他人绝不能知道此事
The men must never find out about this.
他们都会觉得受到了背叛
They'll all feel betrayed.
让桂妮维尔冷静  千万别乱说
Keep Guinevere under control and quiet.
那摩根呢
What about Morgan?
我会去找她的
Oh, I'll get to her.
但得先找到亚瑟
I have to find Arthur first.
我所有的努力  又有人阻碍我的计划
All I've worked for, and it's people who get in the way again.
坏事的总是人
Always people.
我要见国王
I need to speak to the king.
-怎么回事  -我的家人需要帮助
- What's the trouble here? - My family need his help.
国王现在不能见你
The king can't see you now.
我要和他说话
I need to speak to him!
像其他人一样等着
Wait your turn like everyone else.
卡米洛特在垂死挣扎呢
Camelot is in its death throes.
一旦谎言被揭穿
Once its lies are exposed,
它就将迅速衰败
it will quickly decay,
人们在恐惧和惊慌之中将会左顾右盼
and people will look around in fear and panic.
而我则会接纳他们
And I will be there to pick them up.
他们会需要我
They will need me.
男人总自称高人一等  他们却
Men claim to be superior, but it's them
比女人更容易被自己的感情驾驭
more than women who are ruled by their passions.
女人能忍男人之不能忍
Women endure what men cannot bear.
所以人民需要一位强势的女王
Which is why people need a strong queen.
把镀金的那条裙子拿来
Bring me the gilded dress.
有人来访吗
Expecting an official visit?
邀请我们的朋友来  我需要些看客
Invite our friends. I'll need an audience.
我知道我伤你有多深
I know how much I've hurt you.
我羞愧不已
I'm so ashamed.
抱我
Hold me.
爱我
Make love to me.
你也是这样吻他的吗
Is this how you kissed him?
你说只有一次
Once, you said.
我怎么知道你没撒谎呢
How do I know you're telling me the truth?
你父亲过世的时候
It happened again on the journey
你去找他的路上又发生了  对不对
you took when your father died, didn't it?
不不不不  我以我的名誉发誓
No, no, no, no. I swear on my honour--
你的名誉
You gave your honour...
已经归亚瑟了
...to Arthur.
我知道我错了
I know what I did was wrong.
我只求你的原谅
I'm just asking you to forgive me.
我也想  但我做不到
And I want to, but I don't know how to.
我配不上你
I don't deserve you.
你早上为何会问起
What made you ask me this morning?
伊格兰说的话让我起疑了
It was something Igraine said.
伊格兰
Igraine...
她说什么了
What did she say?
我要是不问你  你会说吗
If I hadn't have asked you, would you have told me?
我宁可撒谎
I'd rather lie,
活在愧疚当中
and live with my guilt
也不愿伤害你
than ever hurt you.
我宁愿你不要撒谎
And I would rather you do anything than lie to me.
你该告诉我的
You should have told me.
我发过誓不会背叛她  不会背叛任何人
I swore I'd never betray her or anyone else.
所以你甚至不打算抵赖了
So you're not even gonna try and deny it.
不  这是事实
No. It's the truth.
永远不要向这里的其他人承认  懂吗
Never admit that to anyon else here. Understand?
不是那么简单的事  我伤了我在乎的人
It's not that easy. I've hurt people I care about.
那些人无关要紧  你是国王
Those people don't matter! You're a king.
你只要对你的领土负责  别的不管
Your responsibility is to your realm! Nothing more.
那你要我怎么做
So what do you suggest I do?
要么掩盖此事
Cover this up,
要么就准备好失去一切
or risk losing everything.
我必须要跟国王说话
I must speak to the king!
你是什么人
Who the hell are you?
-陛下  求您  -你有何事
- Your Majesty, please! - What do you want?
我家人在巴尔东被包围了
My family is under siege at Bardon Pass.
你叫什么
What's your name?
阿尔比恩  陛下
Albion, Majesty.
我父亲  他派我来告诉您
My father, he sent me to tell you
有人在袭击巴尔东
that men are attacking Bardon Pass.
必须保卫巴尔东
The Bardon Pass has to be defended.
让大家集合
I want the men assembled now.
巴尔东是进入卡米洛特主要商道
Bardon Pass is the main trade route into Camelot.
若失去这条路  大家就会说我们软弱
If we lose that, word wil spread of our weakness,
我们的领土就会受到威胁
and all our land could come under threat.
我们要保护那家人  保护我们的领地
We protect the family and our territory.
不能有任何妥协
Nothing less is acceptable.
怎么不见里昂提斯
Where's Leontes?
巴尔东受袭
Bardon Pass is under attack.
你的人需要你
Your men need you.
我要回家  回我的村子去
I'm going home to my village.
这里就是你的家  我们是你的家人
This is your home. We are your family.
履行你对国王的誓言
Fulfil your oath to your king,
否则你的荣誉将毁于一旦
or your honour counts for nothing.
跟国王说所谓的荣誉去吧
You talk to the king of honour.
他玷污了我的新娘
He fucked my bride.
此事了结  亚瑟会承担责任
And Arthur will be held to account when this is over.
但是现在我们有危机要处理
But right now we have a crisis on our hands,
你对你的人有一份责任
and you have a duty to your men.
等我回来
When I return,
就与卡米洛特一刀两断
I'm done with Camelot.
那要由你和你妻子来决定了
That's for you and your wife to decide.
桂妮维尔  让他去吧
Guinevere! Leave the men be!
你觉得我凭什么还会听你的
What makes you think I'm ever going to listen to you again?
我告诉过你离他远点  你没听我的
I told you to stay away from him, but you didn't listen to me.
所以你就告诉里昂提斯我背叛他了
So you tell Leontes I betrayed him?
-我什么都没说  -只有你知道
- No, I didn't say anything. - You are the only one who knew.
桂妮维尔  请听我说
Guinevere, please,
这里发生的诡异之事
there are things that have gone on here that are far,
远超你的想象
far more wicked than anything that you have done.
有时间时我会解释的
In time I will explain.
里昂提斯忘带他的祈祷书了
Leontes forgot his prayer book.
他上战场总是带着的
He never goes to battle without it.
你真的觉得
Do you really think
他现在会想见你吗
that he wants to see you now?
只有那一次
It was once.
只有一次啊
Only once.
不急啊  里昂提斯
No hurry, Leontes.
我们只是都等着你罢了
We're all only waiting for you.
高文
Gawain...
别让国王离开你的视线
Never let the king out of your sight.
要是里昂提斯企图伤害亚瑟  就阻止他
If Leontes moves to hurt Arthur, step in.
里昂提斯
Leontes?
现在别质疑我的话
Don't question me. Not now.
要是他或者任何人要伤害国王
If he or anyone else makes to harm the king,
你要做你该做的
do what you have to do.
笑一笑  装得像我刚讲了个笑话
Now, smile, like I've taught you a joke.
好了  我们走
All right, let's move!
胜利归来
Be victorious!
-为了卡米洛特  -为了卡米洛特
- For Camelot! - For Camelot!
为了卡米洛特
For Camelot!
现在商道全无安全可言
The trade routes are now completely unsafe!
国王的旗帜毫无效力
The banner of the king means nothing!
先生们  拜托
Gentlemen, please!
求你们
Please.
要对我弟弟有信心
We must have faith in my brother.
信任替代不了信心
Faith is no substitute for real confidence!
我绝不会背叛亚瑟
I will not heed disloyalty against Arthur.
那不是他的错
It's not his fault
如果有无耻小人在他面前蛊惑
if there are rogue elements within his court
他便很难控制局面
that are difficult for him to control.
谁是无耻小人
What rogue elements?
传闻他的巫师对他影响很大
His sorcerer is rumoured to have a great deal of influence.
据说他的行为...有时会鲁莽
He's been known to act... rashly at times.
不听国王指挥吗
Independent of the king's wishes?
-有些人说他疯了  -为了权利吗
- Some say that's he's mad. - What, for power?
不管他如何疯狂
However mad he is,
我们的国王都有能力控制
our king will keep him in check.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
你要去彭德拉根城堡  是吗
You're going to Castle Pendragon, aren't you?
-你别跟去  -我想看到她被惩罚
- You're not coming. - I want to see her punished.
我不该让她亲近
I should never have let her get close.
但你没克制住  是吗
But you didn't, did you?
你是让我亲近
You let me get close.
如果你当时是那样想的  我很高兴
If that's what you were thinking, I'm glad.
只是很抱歉  那不是真的我
I'm just sorry I wasn't really there.
我也很遗憾
So am I.
我们去彭德拉根城堡
We'll go to Castle Pendragon,
把她带回来
bring her back
在国王为她的背叛承担罪责之前
drag her back if we have to
绑都要把她绑回来
before the king to answer for her treason.
摩根必需臣服于卡米洛特
Morgan must submit to the authority of Camelot.
他们在那儿
There they are.
敌众我寡
We're vastly outnumbered.
亚瑟  如果我们正面进攻
Arthur, we'll be far too exposed
就会在开阔地过早暴露
if we approach from the front.
你说过还有条小路
You said there was another way?
我们得弃马而行
We'll have to leave the horses here.
就在上面
It's just up there.
好  到我前面去  上
Right. Get across me. Go.
里昂提斯
Leontes.
没事  到我前面去
It's fine. Come past me.
做人梯  里昂提斯
Set, Leontes?
用力
Push.
我们是来帮忙的  孩子
We're the help, son!
-格里菲斯  是我们  -阿尔比恩
- Griffith, it's us! - Albion!
你找到他们了
You got them!
拉我们一把
Give us a hand.
用力  老兄
Come on, old man.
是他吗
Is that him?
-我是亚瑟  -过来  见见我父亲
- I'm Arthur. - Come. See my father.
阿尔比恩  你成功了  好孩子
Albion! Ah, you did it! Good lad!
他们今早开始集结
They've been gathering since morning.
谢谢你们来帮忙  殿下
Thank you for coming, Your Highness.
-你肯定是卢坎了  -是
- You must be Lucan. - Yes.
先办正事  我们的徽旗
First things first: our colours.
过来
Come.
正如摩根所料  他们来了
So they came, exactly as Morgan predicted.
她很了解她的家人
She knows her family well.
她确信她兄弟不会坐视不理
She swore her brother wouldn't ignore a lost cause.
那就是他
There he is.
-我们人数是他们的四倍  -不可低估他们
- We outnumber them 4 to 1. - Don't underestimate them.
摩根说他们训练有素
Morgan says they're highly trained.
-我们会盯紧他们  -很好
- Then we'll keep them locked in. - Perfect.
我要弑杀国王
A king to the slaughter.
这是我报效摩根的方式
This is my way to Morgan.
我要将国王之剑交于她
I'll deliver her the king's sword.
她将屈膝谢恩于我
She'll be on her knees to me in gratitude.
我们在等他们进攻
We've been waiting for them to attack.
对  他们人数占优
Well, they have the numbers,
但我们居高临下  这是很大的优势
but we have the tower; it's a good vantage point.
弓箭手居高对我们有利
Archers up there might help us.
但我们弓箭会耗尽
Until we've run out of arrows.
我们会尽力保护你家
We'll secure your home before that happens.
我去检查布防  看看是否有漏洞
I'll check the layout; see if there are any weaknesses.
这些人是谁
Who are all these people?
王土之内已无宁日
There are attacks going on throughout the realm.
无力防备之人只能聚集于此
The undefended are flocking here.
寻求庇护
For protection.
她在哪里
Where is she?
摩根小姐事务繁忙
Lady Morgan is consumed with her task.
她没空
She's unavailable.
她必须见我
Not to me, she isn't.
摩根
Morgan!
你在哪里
Where are you?
你就像条毒蛇躲于暗处吗
Hiding in the dark like the poisonous snake you are?
冷静点  巫师
Calm down, sorcerer.
你怎么来了
Why have you come here?
巫术
Witchcraft.
劫持
Abduction.
叛逆
Treason!
你对这些指控有何回应
How do you answer to these charges?
我不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
你否认用魔法变成别人的容貌吗
So you deny using magic to assume another's shape?
这里这么多人  只有你在无端指责我
You of all people dare hurl such accusations at me.
你挟持了伊格兰
You abducted Igraine,
殴打她
had her beaten,
变作她的模样  穿行于卡米洛特
and walked through Camelot wearing her face.
胡说八道
That's not true.
现在摩根是我们唯一信任的人
Morgan is the only one we can trust right now!
这是干嘛  愚人大合唱吗
What is this? Hmm? Your chorus of fools?
他们都是国王的良民
They are the good people of the realm.
她绑住我  把我囚禁起来
She tied me up! Held me prisoner!
折磨我
Tormented me!
可怜的女人肯定被蛊惑了
Poor woman is clearly deluded.
我还记得那房间
I remember the room.
那儿有标记  女巫的标记
There were markings... witches' markings!
这里根本没有这样的房间
There is no such room here.
就是这里
It's here.
明明就是这里
It was in here.
我发誓之前是在这里
I swear it was.
这里是和平与祈祷之所
This is a place of peace and prayer.
这下面应该有标记
There are markings under here.
我们光明磊落
We have nothing to hide.
还有个护卫叫道纳尔
There was a guard named Donal.
他曾和我一起在这里
He was in here with me.
后来他出什么事了
Then what happened to him?
你良心上一定承受着
You must have so many heavy sins
太多罪孽  孩子
on your conscience, child.
你不需要忏悔吗
Is there nothing you need to confess?
她想让他们相信  我们都疯了
She is trying to convince them that we're mad.
但我知道这里发生过什么
But I know what happened in here.
她经常像这样吗
Is she often like this?
有个男孩叫瑞德伍德
There was a boy named Redwald.
他与这一切毫无瓜葛
He was an innocent in all this.
现在他死了
Now he's dead.
你告诉我有何用
Why are you telling me?
我知道你有份参与
I know you're a part of this.
你要给国王一个交代
You will answer to the king.
我很期待
I look forward to that.
用力  拉
Come on. Pull.
使劲拉
Pull.
好了  就放这里
Right there. Right there.
里昂提斯
Leontes.
别责怪她
Don't blame her.
都是我的错
It was all me.
我要逮捕你
I am arresting you.
在法庭上你将被指控叛国罪
And you will stand charges of treason at court.
你不能逮捕她  她是摩根·彭德拉根
You can't arrest her. She's Morgan Pendragon!
我能这样做  也会这样做
I can, and I will,
以国王的名义
in the name of the king.
梅林  这太荒谬了
Merlin, this is completely absurd.
我要用武力把你带走
I will take you by force.
武力
Force?
卡米洛特承诺
All these people were promised
用武力保护所有这些人
protection by Camelot's force.
但你们的承诺现在何处
But where is it now?
他们的家园被攻击
Their homes are being attacked,
你们不用武力保护他们
and you'd turn your force on me
却来对付我吗
instead of protecting them?
亚瑟在哪里
Where is Arthur?
在你难以触及之处
Safe from your reach.
整个国家都在流血
While the entire country bleeds,
你却闯入这里无端指控我
you storm in here with your insane charges.
我们不会听之任之  卫兵
We won't allow it! Guards!
抓住他们
Hold them!
人心向我  巫师
The people are with me, sorcerer.
把他们绑起来  双手捆牢
Tie them up. Bind their hands securely.
你不明白吗
Don't you understand?
人们已经不信任国王
The people have lost faith in the king.
他们的家园遭受攻击
Their homes are under attack.
所以他们就来求助你和摩根
So they come here to you and Morgan.
我们绝不会抛弃他们
We would never turn away the needy.
你们真圣洁
How very saintly of you.
你在人们的拥戴下
You brought your king to the throne
协助国王登上了宝座
with the support of the people.
现在他失了民心
Now he's lost their support.
你该何去何从呢
Where does that leave you?
很好
Oh, very good.
你把我们玩弄于股掌之间
Play us at our own game.
你到底是什么角色
Who are you?
这与你有何关系
Why does this even matter to you?
我是摩根的慰藉之源
I am a source of solace to Morgan.
傀儡还是操纵者
Puppet or puppeteer?
这问题我一直没想明白
You see, that's what I can't quite work out.
他们对你也有同样的疑问
They ask the same about you.
你为摩根效劳
And what is it you get in return
能得到什么回报呢
for doing Morgan's work?
为摩根效劳就是种奖赏
Service is its own reward.
很聪明  我有点欣赏你了
Clever. I could grow to like you.
在卡米洛特多事之秋
Building alliances quietly
悄悄地建立联盟
while fomenting disquiet in Camelot.
那是她魅力所致
Her delusions must be contagious.
就这样了
Is this it?
任凭他们扣押我们当作人质吗
Do we just let them hold us hostage?
是的
Yes.
一个强大的巫师
A mighty sorcerer,
被一根绳子  绑住
constrained... by a rope.
如果这是人们的意愿
If this is the will of the people,
那就这样吧
so be it,
但你最好有心理准备  小修女
but you'd better be confident, little nun,
因为我可以等待
because I can wait.
我的耐心超乎你的想像
I have more patience than you can ever imagine.
或许关于你魔法的传说
Or perhaps the stories of your sorcery
都只是杜撰的故事
are just stories after all.
卡米洛特不是建立在魔法之上
Camelot isn't built on magic,
而是依靠人民  依靠他们的信任
but on people, on their faith.
我相信他们终究会看穿你们的伎俩
I have this belief they'll see through your ploys.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
没事
I'm fine.
出什么事了
What's wrong?
现在不便说  凯
Not now, Kay.
是我和国王之间的事
It's between me and the king.
有一名骑士过来了
There's a rider coming!
骑士逼近
Rider approaching!
这是怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
瞄准骑士  放箭
Target the rider! Arrows!
是桂妮维尔
It's Guinevere!
不  不
No. No!
桂妮维尔
Guinevere!
亚瑟
Arthur!
是国王
It's the king!
是国王  瞄准国王
It's the king! Target the king!
我说跑  你就拼命跑
When I say "Now", you run as best you can.
好
All right.
跑
Go now!
快跑  快
Go! Move!
快跑  接住她
Run! Take her!
快走  欧菲尔斯
Go! Ulfius!
快带她离开这里
Take her! Get her out of here!
-你做过什么  -什么意思
- What did you do?! - What do you mean?
你做过什么
What did you do?!
放开国王  凯
Hands of the king, Kay!
我了解你  你做了什么
I know you! What happened?!
-凯  -里昂提斯
- Kay! - Leontes.
告诉他们
Tell them!
我背叛了里昂提斯
I betrayed Leontes.
以最恶劣的方式背叛了他
In the worst way I could have.
不
No...
就在我婚礼当天早上
It was the morning of my wedding.
他比我先占有了她
He had her first.
然后他做了我们的证婚人
And then he married us.
-凯  -别跟我说话
- Kay-- - Don't talk to me.
凯
Kay!
你就是死性难改  是吧
You just can't stop yourself, can you?
任何女人你都赶出手
Any woman is fair game.
不是那样  从来都不是那样
It's not like that, and it never is.
别找借口了  我听够了
Don't try to find an excuse; I've heard them all before.
-我爱她  -那是当然
- I love her. - Of course you do!
就像你爱其他那些女人一样
Like you loved all the others!
我爱她  可她嫁给了别人  我接受了现实
I love her, but she married someone else, and I accept that.
你接受了
You accept it?
你毁了里昂提斯的婚姻  还好意思说你接受了
After you destroyed Leontes' marriage.
怎么  你希望他  希望我们都无视这事吗
And, what, he's expected, we're expected, to ignore it?!
你以前就这德行
'Cause that's what you're used to
从小时候起  这种事就没停过
it's what always happens, ever since we were boys.
-不  这次不一样  -一样
- No, this isn't the same. - It is!
因为你狗改不了吃屎
Because you never change!
你不配为王
You're not a worthy king.
你甚至不配做我的兄弟
You're not even a worthy brother.
反正咱们从来就无血缘关系
At least we were never linked by blood.
你又回来了  并且又要不光彩地离开了
Again you return, and again you leave in disgrace.
还有你  梅林
And you, Merlin,
你真该留在我离开你的那温柔乡里
you should have stayed in bed where I left you.
他们试图逮捕我  将我绑去卡米洛特
They tried to arrest me and drag me to Camelot!
好啊  我这就去卡米洛特
Well, I will go to Camelot!
我要去揭露这巫师的恶行
I will expose the corruption of this sorcerer,
然后辅佐我王弟  重整朝纲
and help the king, my brother, to restore order.
让所有人都能在我这里
Let all who seek a safe harbour
找到他们渴求的安定
find one with me.
里昂提斯
Leontes.
你为何前来
Who did you come here for?
为了你
You.
只为了你
Only you.
别无视我
Don't ignore me!
-一切还没结束  -你怎么知道
- This is not over!  - How can you be so sure?
因为在我们婚礼当天
Because I made a promise
我曾在上帝面前起誓
on our wedding day in front of God.
你忘了带这个
You left without it.
你留着吧
Keep it.
可它是你的
But it's yours.
你以前不也是我的么
You were mine too.
-让一让  -是谁啊
- Make way. - Who is it?
现在是跟他们谈话的绝佳时机
The perfect opportunity to talk to them.
袭击起作用了
The attacks are working.
是谁
Who is it?
这些是什么人
Who are all these people?
边境发生了一系列袭击事件
There's been a series of attacks at the boundaries.
这些都是来自边境的受难家庭
There are all families from frontier houses across the realm.
他们正赶往卡米洛特
They're heading for Camelot.
他们害怕留在家乡被害
They're scared to be at home.
我叫摩根·彭德拉根
My name is Morgan Pendragon.
我正带两名谋反者
I'm taking 2 conspirators
去卡米洛特接受国王的判决
to Camelot to face the king's justice.
如果你们跟我一道启程  我会保你们平安
If you leave with me now, I can promise you protection.
走吧
Let's go.
跟着摩根
Go with Morgan.
你们无需害怕任何事
You have nothing to fear now.
在卡米洛特你们将会很安全
You will be safe at Camelot.
跟我们一起走吧
Come with us. Come with us.
这些人信任摩根渐渐超过了信任亚瑟
All these people are starting to believe Morgan over Arthur.
我们得做点什么
We have to do something. You have to.
这是陷阱  这就是她的意图
That's the trap. That's what she wants.
现在使用任何巫术都会正中她的下怀
Any hint of sorcery now will play into her hands
会让人们对我们反目相向
and turn the people against us for good.
如果能阻止她
Well, maybe we have to take that risk
也许我们应该冒险一试
just to stop her.
这些人永远不会跟从我们的
These people will never follow us.
我们不是解决问题的关键
We're not the solution to this.
那什么才是
Then what is?
亚瑟
Only Arthur.
你我只是星星之火
You and I, we're the sparks that made him.
现在他必须自己燃起燎原之势
He has to become the flame now.
他必须依靠自己来获胜
He has to prevail by his own design.
无论他们如何挑衅
Whatever the provocation,
你我都要坚强忍受并且缄口不言
you and I must stay strong and silent,
对你的儿子有点信心吧  答应我
and have faith in your son. Promise me.
你确定这是最好的方法吗
Are you sure this is the best approach?
只有这样
This way Arthur will see
亚瑟才能看清他姐姐的真面目
his sister's true colours once and for all.
这将纠正他对她的错误感觉
This will finally break the misplaced loyalty he feels to her.
-快点  -看
- Hurry. - Look.
我有话要对国王说
I want to talk to the king.
那就说吧
So talk.
你们有一次投降的机会
You have one chance to surrender.
你真不该浪费精力走过来
You could have saved yourself a walk.
你们杀了我的守卫
You killed my guards!
威胁到了我的领土
You threatened my territory!
那今天就是你们的死期了
Then today you die.
滚你妈的
Fuck you!
高文  稳住
Gawain, hold.
准备进攻
Prepare for the attack.
来吧  你们听到他的话了
Come on! You heard him!
进攻
Attack!
欧菲尔斯  带她离开
Ulfius, get her out of her!
凯
Kay!
阿尔比恩  进去
Albion! Get inside!
-母亲  母亲  -去找你父亲
- Mother! Mother! - Get your father.
亚瑟
Arthur!
你得下令撤退  我们死伤太过惨重了
You have to sound a retreat. We've lost too many men!
这他妈算什么  我说过让你几个像样的
What the hell is this mess? I told you to find the best men!
我找了
I did!
可对手太精明  而且他们都受过良好的训练
But those men are clever, and they're well trained!
母亲  我们会救你的
Mother, we'll help you.
欧菲尔斯
Ulfius!
撤退
Fall back!
-搭把手  -快撤
- Bring a hand! - Hurry!
快来帮我一把
Come on, help me!
-撤回原位  -撤
- Back to positions! - Back!!
回到原位
Back to your positions!
凯
Kay!
-放下他  -他们在撤退
- Put him down. - They're retreating!
欧菲尔斯牺牲了
Ulfius is dead.
够了
Then that's it.
带上凯和这家人  从我们过来的小路撤离
Take Kay, take the family, and go out the way we came in.
我会在前方分散他们的注意力
I'll create a diversion from the front,
为你们争取撤退的时间
give you time to get away.
-那你呢  -我随后就来
- What about you? - I'll be right behind you.
必须有人去分散他们的注意力
Someone needs to provide the diversion.
-但不能让你去  -我们已有一死两伤
- Not you, though. - We have 1 dead and 2 injured.
必须让他们安全撤离
We have to get them to safety.
我知道这关口很重要  但你们已经尽力了
I know the pass is important, but you've done all you could.
别管这地方了  跟我们一起走吧
Forget about it now. Come with us.
我留下
I'll stay.
-你走  -不行
- You go. - No.
不得争论  不得辩驳
No discussions, no arguments.
我要所有人立即离开  帮我扶凯起来
I want everyone out of here. Now! Help me get Kay.
来吧
Come on.
要让他们以为我们都还在这里
We'll make them think that we're all still here,
为你们争取时间撤离  快走吧
give you time to escape. Now get a move on.
没时间了
We don't have any time.
亚瑟  梅林命我保护你
Arthur. I have orders from Merlin to protect you.
我不需要保护了
I don't need protecting any more.
听着  我知道你想做什么
Look, I know what you're doing,
可你不能为了摆平一切
but you're not going to set everything else straight
就做傻事
with some stupid gesture.
听着  带伤员去那栋损毁的建筑
Listen, take the injured to the ruined building
从小路过去  我随后就到
we passed on the way in. I'll follow on--
没准还会比你们先到呢
probably get there before you.
我们另一边再会
I'll see you on the other side.
小心脚下  接住她  伙计们
Mind your footing. Got her, boys.
-放松  勇敢点  -是
- Easy. Be brave. - Yes.
懦夫
Cowards!!
你们就这么点本事了吗
Is that all you've got?! This...
这片土地属于你们的国王
...land belongs to your king!
我们会誓死保卫这里
And we will protect it to the death!
他们在嘲笑我们  华莱士
They're taunting us, Wallace.
你喜欢被嘲笑吗
Are you enjoying being taunted?
我已经派人去请求支援了
I've sent for reinforcements.
他们太强了  跟我们不是一个档次的
They're too good for us to attack just on level numbers.
我向摩根保证过会从亚瑟的尸体上带回他的剑
I promised Morgan I would take Arthur's sword from his dead body.
我不会让她失望的
I will not let her down.
亚瑟王将死于我们之手
King Arthur dies at our hands.
今晚  就在此地
Here. Tonight.
决一死战
To the death.